Finding Aid for Sullivan Dexter Green papers [microform], 1853-1890
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Sullivan Dexter Green papers [microform] 1853-1890
Green, Sullivan Dexter, 1833-1889.
0.3 linear feet, 1 roll microfilm
851368 Aa 2
Student at University of Michigan, 1855-1858, officer in Co. F, 24th Michigan Infantry and correspondent for the Detroit Free Press during the Civil War. Student letters and other correspondence, notes on baseball games played in Detroit, Michigan, in 1867, diary of a trip to Detroit in 1854, diary of daily activities in New Hampshire in 1856, newspaper clippings of war reports, edition of temperance newspaper which he published himself; and drawings.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The materials were purchased. 1771
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open without restriction. Researcher must use microfilm copy.
The originals of the microfilmed papers ate at the Bentley Historical Library.
Sullivan Dexter Green attended the University of Michigan from 1855 to 1858. During the Civil War, Green was quartermaster sergeant, Co. F, 24th Michigan Infantry. He also was a correspondent of the Detroit Free Press during the war. He died December 29, 1889 in Berlin Falls, New Hampshire.
The Green papers concern his activities at the University of Michigan in the 1850s and his Civil War service. The collection consists of correspondence, diaries, clippings, and miscellaneous. Of interest is a folder of line drawings depicting Civil War scenes.
Subjects:
Baseball.; Detroit (Mich.)--Description and travel.; Detroit free press.; New Hampshire.; Temperance--United States.; Voyages and travels.; Travelers.; United States. Army. Michigan Infantry Regiment, 24th (1862-1865). Company F.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; University of Michigan--Students--Correspondence.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1851-1860.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Military life.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States. Army. Michigan Infantry Regiment, 24th (1862-1865). Company F.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Drawings.
- Personal papers: University of Michigan, Civil War, etc.
  - Correspondence, 1853-1872, 1890
    - 1853-1860 (Reel 1)
    - 1861-1865 (Reel 1)
    - 1871-1872 (Reel 1)
    - 1890 (Reel 1)
  - Diaries
    - 1854 (Reel 1)
    - 1856 (Reel 1)
  - Diary Fragments
    - 1849 (Reel 1)
    - 1858 (Reel 1)
    - 1863 (Reel 1)
  - Line Drawings of Civil War Scenes (Reel 1)
  - Civil War Correspondence (misc. correspondents), 1864-1865 (Reel 1)
  - Newspaper clippings
    - 1862-1865 (Reel 1)
    - 1872-1889 (Reel 1)
  - Notes of Detroit Baseball Games (Reel 1)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material (Reel 1)
  - Miscellanea (Reel 1)